Fritz Kreisler Collection
Music Division, Library of Congress
Guides to Special Collections in the Music Division of the Library of Congress
Fritz Kreisler Collection1845-1969 (bulk 1910-1955)
ML31.K7
Kreisler, Fritz, 1875-1962
around 1,800 items 25 boxes 14 linear feet
Music Division Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
Fritz Kreisler was an Austrian-born American violinist and composer. The collection contains Kreisler's original compositions in sketch, manuscript (including holographs), and printed form. In addition, it contains manuscript and heavily annotated printed copies of Kreisler's transcriptions of other composers' music. It also contains correspondence, financial and legal documents, programs, clippings, writings, photographs, awards and honors. The collection includes the papers of Kreisler's biographer Louis Lochner, which contain Kreisler's personal papers and material related to the biography.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the Library's online catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically therein.
People
Kreisler, Fritz, 1875-1962--Archives.; Kreisler, Fritz, 1875-1962--Correspondence.; Kreisler, Fritz, 1875-1962--Manuscripts.; Kreisler, Fritz, 1875-1962--Photographs.; Kreisler, Fritz, 1875-1962.; Kreisler, Fritz, 1875-1962.; Kreisler, Fritz, 1875-1962. Selections.; Lochner, Louis Paul, 1887-1975.; Lochner, Louis Paul, 1887-1975. Fritz Kreisler.
Subjects
Composers--Correspondence.; Composers.; Music--Manuscripts.; Violinists--Correspondence.; Violinists.
Titles
Kreisler collection, 1845-1969
Form/Genre
Artifacts (Object genre); Awards.; Clippings (Information artifacts); Correspondence.; Financial records.; Photographic prints.
Administrative Information
Provenance
Gift of Fritz Kreisler, 1955; the Kreisler estate, 1970-1971; and Louis Lochner, 1960.
Accruals
No further accruals are expected.
Access and Restrictions
The Fritz Kreisler Collection is open to research. Researchers are advised to contact the Music Division prior to visiting in order to determine whether the desired materials will be available at that time.
Certain restrictions to use or copying of materials may apply.
Biographical Sketch
Date Event
1875, Feb. 2 Born in Vienna to Samuel and Anna Kreisler
1882-1885 Studied at the Vienna Conservatory with Joseph Hellmesberger (violin) and Anton Bruckner (harmony and theory)
1885 Won gold medal of the Vienna Conservatory
1885-1887 Studied in Paris with Joseph Lambert Massart (violin) and Léo Delibes (composition)
1887 Won Premier Grand Prix of the Paris Conservatoire
1888, Nov. 9 While on tour with pianist Moriz Rosenthal, made American debut with the Boston Symphony conducted by Walter Damrosch
1890-1896 Spent two years at Piaristen Gymnasium to pass his Abitur Took two years of pre-medical training Spent two years as a soldier in the Kaiserjäger Regiment of Austrian army
1896-1898 Frequented the Tonkünstlerverein and Café Grünsteidl in Vienna with Brahms, Joachim, Wolf, Heuberer, and Hellmesberger
1899-1902 Performed in concerts in the United States and throughout Europe and Scandinavia
1902 Nov. Married Harriet Woerz (née Lies) in New York City
1910 Sept. Copyrighted Caprice Viennois, Liebesfreud, Tambourin Chinois, and Liebeslied
1910, Nov. 10 Performed world premiere of Elgar's Violin Concerto in B minor, which is dedicated to him
1914 Aug. Served one year as a lieutenant in the Austro-Hungarian army
1915 Published Four Weeks in the Trenches with Macmillan & Company
1917-1919 Retired from performing for money due to American resentment over his service in the Austro-Hungarian army
1919-1935 Performed throughout the world, including the Near and Far East, Scandinavia, Russia, Australia, and South America
1921 Wrote "Music and Life" for The Mentor
1932, Dec. 23 Premiere in Vienna, of his operetta Sissy, the Rose from Bavaria-land
1935, Mar. 3 After Kreisler was questioned by Harold Spivacke about the actual provenance of the Classical Manuscripts, Olin Downes reveals in the New York Times that the series is Kreisler's own original compositions rather than transcriptions
1938 May Awarded the French Legion of Honor; assumed French citizenship (officially granted in May 1939)
1940-1945 Made charitable appearances to benefit organizations such as the American Red Cross, the Salvation Army, the Metropolitan Opera Association Fund, and the Musician's Emergency Fund
1941, Apr. 27 Skull fractured in traffic accident in New York City
1942 Oct. Successful return to concert stage at Carnegie Hall
1944, July 7 Radio debut on the Bell Telephone Hour with the NBC Symphony Orchestra conducted by Donald Voorhees
1947, Nov. 1 Final concert at Carnegie Hall
1949 Jan. Public auction at Parke-Bernet Galleries of Kreisler's rare books, manuscripts, and artifacts earned over $120,000 for the Golden Rule Foundation and Lenox Hill Hospital
1962, Jan. 29 Died, New York City
Scope and Content Note
Fritz Kreisler is known predominantly for his artistry as a violinist, particularly in performances of his own transcriptions and cadenzas, but he is also worthy of note as a composer. More than fifty of Kreisler's original compositions are represented in this collection, in sketch, manuscript, or printed form. Holographs of some of Kreisler's most popular compositions, such as Caprice viennois, Liebesfreud, and the Viennese rhapsodic fantasietta, are complemented by his manuscripts of less well-known works, including Drei Nachtgesänge (with poetry by Eichendorff) and his Song, op. 7, for violin and piano. Included among the holographs are several works of the Klassische Manuskripte series, a set of 14 pieces for violin and piano that were thought to be Kreisler's transcriptions of classical works until 1935, when it was revealed that they were his original compositions. Kreisler's Viennese light opera Sissy (1932) is also represented in the collection, both by holograph full scores of most of its individual numbers and by a complete printed vocal score.
Approximately 130 of Kreisler's transcriptions are included in the collection, adaptations of works by composers ranging from Corelli to Moussorgsky to Stephen Foster and Percy Grainger. The manuscripts and heavily annotated prints of Kreisler's transcriptions reveal the compositional process through which his characteristic virtuosic sound was achieved. For many such works there are 2 or more manuscript versions to compare with the holograph annotations to the printed edition.
The musical manuscripts and printed scores in the collection are by far its largest component, but they are supplemented by a number of Kreisler's personal papers, including correspondence, financial and legal documents, photographs, and honors. There are also various papers relating to Kreisler's violins and bows, and a collection of programs, itineraries, and clippings relevant to his activities as a performer.
The papers that journalist Louis Lochner (1887-1975) donated to the Library in 1960 are divided into two categories: those relating directly to Kreisler, and those pertaining to Lochner's 1950 biography, Fritz Kreisler. Kreisler's papers include letters, legal documents, and honors, as well as writings, programs, press releases, and clippings about Kreisler. Lochner's own papers in the collection consist of notes and corrections for his biography, relevant correspondence, and other miscellaneous source material.
Claudia Widgery, May 1992
Organization of the Fritz Kreisler Collection
The Fritz Kreisler Collection is organized in eleven series:
Music, 1845-1966
Writings, 1845-1966
Correspondence
Performance Materials
Clippings, 1910-1969
Photographs, 1845-1966
Honors & Awards, 1875-1962
Financial Papers, 1875-1962
Legal Documents, 1875-1962
Miscellany, 1875-1962
Louis Lochner Papers, 1875-1962
http://lccn.loc.gov/2010563512
Container List
- Music, 1845-1966 (Box 1-13, 23)
  Fritz Kreisler is known predominantly for his artistry as a violinist, particularly in performances of his own transcriptions and cadenzas, but he is also worthy of note as a composer. More than fifty of Kreisler's original compositions are represented in this collection, in sketch, manuscript, or printed form. Holographs of some of Kreisler's most popular compositions, such as Caprice viennois, Liebesfreud, and the Viennese rhapsodic fantasietta, are complemented by his manuscripts of less well-known works, including Drei Nachtgesänge (with poetry by Eichendorff) and his Song, op. 7, for violin and piano. Included among the holographs are several works of the Klassische Manuskripte series, a set of 14 pieces for violin and piano that were thought to be Kreisler's transcriptions of classical works until 1935, when it was revealed that they were his original compositions. Kreisler's Viennese light opera Sissy (1932) is also represented in the collection, both by holograph full scores of most of its individual numbers and by a complete printed vocal score.
  Approximately 130 of Kreisler's transcriptions are included in the collection, adaptations of works by composers ranging from Corelli to Moussorgsky to Stephen Foster and Percy Grainger. The manuscripts and heavily annotated prints of Kreisler's transcriptions reveal the compositional process through which his characteristic virtuosic sound was achieved. For many such works there are 2 or more manuscript versions to compare with the holograph annotations to the printed edition.
  - Kreisler as Composer (Box 1-5, 13, 23)
    Arranged alphabetically by title.
    - Andantino [in the style of Martini], Holograph full score in pencil; 3 p.; Also: Chanson Louis XIII et Pavane [in the style of Couperin]. Holograph full score in pencil; 6 p. Praeludium und allegro [in the style of Pugnani]. Holograph full score in pencil; [11 p.] (Box-folder 1/1)
    - Act I. No. 4. Letter Song - Nancy & girls, Manuscript full score in ink with blue pencil annotations; 29 p.; Uniform title: Apple blossoms. Act I, no. 5, Letter song (Box-folder 1/2)
    - Dance. Act 2., Manuscript full score in ink; 12 p.; On first page: Extra number in Apple Blossoms (not used); Uniform title: Apple blossoms. Excerpt (not in final work) (Box-folder 1/3)
    - [As I tread the road that winds], Holograph piano-vocal score; 3 p.; Upper left of first page: Dec. 5, 1929 / C. J. F.; Uniform title: As I tread the road that winds (Box-folder 1/4)
    - Ballads from the Scotch minstrelsy New York: Carl Fischer, 1917., Printed piano-vocal score; 2 copies; Arranged by Fritz Kreisler, in collaboration with Reinhold Warlich; Laid in: Loch Lomond; New York: Charles Foley, 1917 (Box-folder 1/5)
    - Ballet; Einlage, Holograph full score in pencil, incomplete; 11 p. (Box-folder 1/6)
    - Burst of melody, A, Manuscript piano-vocal score in ink; 7 p.; Words by Charles A. Wagner (Box-folder 1/7)
    - Caprice viennois, Holograph full score in ink with annotations; 13 p.; At end of music: F. K., 1912 (Box-folder 1/8)
    - Caprice viennois, Holograph full score in pencil; [12 p.] (Box-folder 1/9)
    - [Caprice viennois, op. 2], Holograph sketches for violin and piano, in pencil; [6 p.]; Uniform title: Caprice viennois, op. 2 (Box-folder 1/10)
    - Caprice viennois New York: Charles Foley, 1910., Printed violin part; 3 p.; Also printed: New York, 1938 (Box-folder 1/11)
    - Cavatina, Holograph score for violin and piano, in pencil; 8 p. (Box-folder 1/12)
    - Chanson Louis XIII, Manuscript score for violin and piano, in pencil; 6 p.; Uniform title: Chanson Louis XIII & pavane (in the style of Louis Couperin) (Box-folder 1/13)
    - Concert von Antonio Vivaldi, C-dur, Holograph full score in pencil; 20 p.; Uniform title: Concerto in the style of Vivaldi, violin & string orchestra, C major (Box-folder 1/14)
    - Violin Concerto von Antonio Vivaldi aus dem Manuskript herausgegeben und bearbeitet von Fritz Kreisler, Copyist's score for violin and piano, in ink, 23 p.; Uniform title: Concerto in the style of Vivaldi, violin & string orchestra, C major; arr. (Box-folder 1/15)
    - Concerto (C dur) von Antonio Vivaldi New York: Carl Fischer, Inc., 1927., Printed score for violin and piano; Bound with: Partita in E major (Bach-Kreisler) [and] La folia (Corelli-Kreisler); Uniform title: Concerto in the style of Vivaldi, violin & string orchestra, C major; arr. (Box-folder 1/16)
    - Cradle song, 1915, Holograph score for voice and orchestra, in ink and pencil; [6 p.]; Under title: based on my Caprice Viennois (Box-folder 1/17)
    - [Drei Nachtgesänge], Holograph piano-vocal score in pencil; 11 p.; Uniform title: Drei Nachtgesänge (Box-folder 1/18)
    - Vier Nachtgesänge von Fritz Kreisler, Holograph piano-vocal score in pencil with red and blue pencil annotations; 9 p.; Words by Eichendorff; Uniform title: Drei Nachtgesänge; Includes: Im Abendrot [not part of final collection] Wir sind durch Not und Freude is not included (Box-folder 1/19)
    - Episode, Holograph score for violin and piano, in pencil; 8 p. (Box-folder 1/20)
    - Fantasie für Violine mit Klavier, Holograph score for violin and piano, and violin part, in ink; 13 p.; Dated: 19 Marz 1883 (Box-folder 1/21)
    - Farewell to Cucullain (Londonderry Air) New York: Charles Foley, 1922., Printed violin part; 3 p.; Transcribed by Fritz Kreisler (Box-folder 1/22)
    - Follow thy star, Ozalid of holograph score for violin and piano, incomplete; 2 p.; On cover; Fritz Kreisler / March 10, 1950 / I don't remember whose poem this is and why I did not finish it. I believe it must have been 40 years ago that I wrote this / F. K. (Box-folder 1/23)
    - French song, Holograph sketch in pencil; 4 p. (Box-folder 1/24)
    - Ghasel, Manuscript piano-vocal score in ink with pencil alterations and annotations; 6 p. (Box-folder 1/25)
    - Vier Nachtgesänge. IV. Ghasel (Gottfried Keller), Manuscript piano-vocal score in pencil; 6 p.; At bottom: Copyright 1921 Carl Fischer, New York / 30737; Uniform title: Ghasel (Box-folder 1/26)
    - Gitana, La, Holograph full score in pencil with annotations; 19 p.; On cover: Dec. 29. 1941 (Box-folder 1/27)
    - Grave [in the style of Wilhelm] Friedemann Bach, Holograph full score in pencil; [4 p.]; Also includes: La précieuse [in the style of] Louis Couperin [6 p.] Allegretto [in the style of] Luigi Boccherini [5 p.] (Box-folder 2/1)
    - Grave [in the style of Wilhelm] Friedemann Bach, Holograph score for violin and piano, in pencil; 3 p. (Box-folder 2/2)
    - Grave [in the style of Wilhelm] Friedemann Bach, Copyist's organ score in ink with violin part written in pencil; 2 p. (Box-folder 2/3)
    - Gypsy caprice, Holograph score for violin and piano, in ink, incomplete; 6 p. (Box-folder 2/4)
    - [Heut vor fünf und zwanzig Jahr], Holograph piano-vocal sketches in pencil; [6 p.]; Uniform title: Heut vor fünf und zwanzig Jahr (Box-folder 2/5)
    - Irish song, Holograph piano-vocal sketch in pencil; 6 p.; Under title: originally conceived for John (Box-folder 2/6)
    - Klassische Manuskripte Mainz: B. Schott's Söhne, 1910., Includes printed scores for violin and piano of the following titles (in order): Chanson Louis XIII and pavane in the style of Couperin Andantino in the style of Martini Menuett in the style of Porpora La précieuse in the style of Couperin Praeludium und allegro in the style of Pugnani Siciliano [and] rigaudon in the style of Francoeur Scherzo in the style of Dittersdorf Allegretto in the style of Boccherini Variationen über ein Thema von Corelli in the style of Tartini Preghiera in the style of Martini Tempo di minuetto in the style of Pugnani Aubade provençale in the style of Couperin La chasse (Caprice) in the style of Cartier Grave in the style of Wilhelm Friedemann Bach (Box-folder 2/7)
    - Liebes-Walzer, Holograph score for violin and piano, in pencil; 7 p. (Box-folder 2/8)
    - Liebesfreud, Holograph full score in pencil with annotations; 22 p.; On cover: Dec. 1941 (Box-folder 2/9)
    - Coda to Liebesfreud, Holograph score for violin and piano, in pencil; 2 p.; At end of p. 1: Fritz Kreisler, Oct. 27th, 1960, New York; Uniform title: Liebesfreud (Box-folder 2/10)
    - [Liebesfreud. Wiener Walzer; arr.], Manuscript full score in ink with annotations; 27 p.; Arranged by F. A. Stock; On cover page: Ballet Musik; Uniform title: Liebesfreud. Wiener Walzer; arr. (Box-folder 2/11)
    - [Liebesfreud. Wiener Walzer; arr.], Manuscript full score in ink with annotations; 11 p.; Arranged by F. A. Stock; Ozalid and negative photostat of manuscript score in oversize box 23, folder 1; Uniform title: Liebesfreud. Wiener Walzer; arr. (Box-folder 2/12)
    - Liebesleid, Holograph full score in pencil; 18 p.; Dated: December 1941 (Box-folder 2/13)
    - Changes in Liebesleid, Holograph sketches for violin and piano, in pencil; 3 p.; Uniform title: Liebesleid. Sketches (Box-folder 2/14)
    - Malagueña, Holograph in ink; 7 p. (Box-folder 2/15)
    - Malagueña New York: Charles Foley, 1937., Printed score for violin and piano; 11 p. (Box-folder 2/16)
    - O Salutaris hostia, Holograph piano-vocal score in pencil; 3 p. (Box-folder 2/17)
    - O Sanctissima (freely adapted to a melody by Arcangelo Corelli), Holograph piano-vocal score in pencil; 6 p. (Box-folder 2/18)
    - Paraphrase on two Russian folk-songs, Holograph score for violin and piano, in pencil; 7 p. (Box-folder 2/19)
    - Petite valse (after a poem of Edna St. Vincent Millay), Holograph score for violin and piano, in ink; 4 p. (Box-folder 2/20)
    - Praeludium - G. Pugnani, Holograph score for violin and piano, in ink and pencil; 8 p.; Uniform title: Praeludium and allegro in the style of Pugnani (Box-folder 2/21)
    - Preludium and allegro., Manuscript full score in ink; 26 p.; Transcribed by Fabien Sevitzky; Uniform title: Praeludium and allegro in the style of Pugnani; arr. (Box-folder 2/22)
    - La précieuse [in the style of Couperin], Holograph score for violin and piano, in pencil; 3 p. (Box-folder 2/23)
    - Romance, Holograph score for violin and piano, in pencil; 5 p. (Box-folder 2/24)
    - Dittersdorf "Scherzo", Holograph full score in pencil; 6 p.; Uniform title: Scherzo in the style of Dittersdorf (Box-folder 2/25)
    - Scherzo [in the style of Dittersdorf], Holograph score for violin and piano, in pencil; 4 p.; Uniform title: Scherzo in the style of Dittersdorf (Box-folder 2/26)
    - Schön Rosmarin, Holograph score for violin and piano, in pencil; 4 p. (Box-folder 13/16)
    - Schön Rosmarin New York: Charles Foley, 1910, 1938., Printed violin part; 3 p.; Plate no. 29030; Also printed: New York, 1938 (Box-folder 2/27)
    - Serenata, Holograph sketch for violin and piano, in pencil, incomplete; 4 p. (Box-folder 2/28)
    - Shepherd's madrigal, Holograph score for violin and piano, in pencil; 6 p. (Box-folder 2/29)
    - Siciliano. Fr. Francoeur, Holograph score for violin and piano, in pencil, with orange and blue pencil; 9 p.; Uniform title: Siciliano et rigaudon in the style of Francoeur (Box-folder 2/30)
    - Siciliano et rigaudon von François Francoeur, Manuscript score for violin and piano, in ink with pencil annotations; 7 p.; Uniform title: Siciliano et rigaudon in the style of Francoeur (Box-folder 2/31)
    - Sissy Wien: Verlag W. Karczag, 1932., Printed piano-vocal score; 138 p.; Singspiel in 2 Akten (4 Bildern) von Ernst und Hubert Marischka nach einem Lustspiel von Ernst Decsey und Gustav Holm (Box-folder 3/1)
    - Duett, Néné und Thurn-Taxis, Akt I, Holograph full score in ink; 18 p.; Uniform title: Sissy. No. 2, Ich hab' dich lieb (Box-folder 3/2)
    - Wiegenlied, Duett (Sissi und Néné), I Akt, Holograph full score in ink with pencil and red pencil annotations; 17 p.; Uniform title: Sissy. No. 3, Ich glaube, das Glück hält mich heute im Arm (Box-folder 3/3)
    - Duett, Max und Kempen, Holograph full score in ink with annotations; 33 p.; Uniform title: Sissy. No. 4, Jeder Mensch hat and're Schwächen (Box-folder 3/4)
    - Sissy, Duett, Max & Kempen, Holograph piano-vocal score in pencil; 6 p.; Uniform title: Sissy. No. 4, Jeder Mensch hat and're Schwächen (Box-folder 3/5)
    - Finale, I Akt, Holograph full (oversize) score in pencil with annotations; 31 p.; Uniform title: Sissy. No. 5, Finale, I Akt (Box-folder 23/2)
    - Finale, I Akt, Sissy, Holograph piano-vocal score in pencil; 10 p.; Uniform title: Sissy. No. 5, Finale, I Akt (Box-folder 3/6)
    - Entre Akt, Holograph full score in pencil; 32 p.; Uniform title: Sissy. No. 5a, Entreakt (Box-folder 3/7)
    - Duett, Pepi - Kempen, Ite Akt, Holograph full score (oversize) in pencil with annotations; 21 p.; Uniform title: Sissy. No. 6, Jeder Mann, selbst ein Philister (Box-folder 23/5)
    - Ich wär' so gern einmal verliebt, Holograph full score in ink with pencil and red pencil annotations; 20 p.; Uniform title: Sissy. No. 7, Ich wär so gern einmal verliebt (Box-folder 3/8)
    - II Akt, Lied (Sissy), Manuscript piano-vocal score in ink; 7 p.; Uniform title: Sissy. No. 7, Ich wär so gern einmal verliebt (Box-folder 3/9)
    - Soldatenlied, Max (II Akt), Holograph full score in ink; 29 p.; Uniform title: Sissy. No. 11, Soldatenlied (Box-folder 3/10)
    - Liebesleid, Duett Néné & Thurn Taxis, Akt II, Holograph full score (oversize) in pencil; 26 p.; Uniform title: Sissy. No. 13, Liebesleid (Box-folder 23/3)
    - Duett, Kempen und Pepi, II Akt, Holograph full score in pencil with annotations; 18 p.; Uniform title: Sissy. No. 15, Warum bist du so fürchterlich bös auf mich (Box-folder 3/11)
    - Duett, Max und Sissy, II Akt, Holograph full score in ink; 20 p.; Uniform title: Sissy. No. 16, Nimm von der Welt (Box-folder 3/12)
    - II. Akt, Finale, Holograph full score (oversize) in pencil with annotations; 74 p.; Uniform title: Sissy. No. 17, Finale, II Akt (Box-folder 23/4)
    - [Sissy. Marsch-Lied], Holograph full score in ink with annotations; 29 p.; Uniform title: Sissy. Marsch-Lied (Box-folder 3/13)
    - Sketch in Sissy for an Austrian song ditty, Holograph full score (oversize) in pencil; [3 p.]; Uniform title: Sissy. Sketch for an Austrian song (Box-folder 23/6)
    - Song, op. 7, Holograph score for violin and piano, in ink; 5 p. (Box-folder 3/14)
    - Spanish valse, Holograph score for violin and piano, in pencil, incomplete; 8 p. (Box-folder 4/1)
    - Stars in my eyes, Holograph full score in pencil; 14 p. (Box-folder 4/2)
    - Stars in my eyes, Holograph score for violin and piano, in ink and pencil; 5 p. (Box-folder 4/3)
    - Streich-quartett, A-moll, Holograph score; 106 p. (Box-folder 13/17)
    - [String quartet. Scherzo burlesco and Finale retrospettivo; arr.], Holograph score for violin and piano, and violin part, in pencil; 35 p.; Uniform title: String quartet. Scherzo burlesco and Finale retrospettivo; arr. (Box-folder 4/4)
    - Tambourin chinois, Holograph full score in pencil with annotations; oblong, 16 p. (Box-folder 4/5)
    - Tambourin chinois, op. 3, Holograph score for violin and piano, in ink and pencil; 6 p. (Box-folder 4/6)
    - Valse, C major, Holograph score for violin and piano, in pencil, unfinished; 8 p.; On cover: not published (Box-folder 4/7)
    - Tartini, Holograph score for violin and piano, in ink; 14 p.; Uniform title: Variations in the style of Tartini (Box-folder 4/8)
    - Variations on a theme by Corelli [in the style of Tartini], Holograph full score in pencil; 5 p. (Box-folder 4/9)
    - Variationen über ein Thema von Corelli, Holograph score for violin and piano, in ink; 4 p.; Uniform title: Variations on a theme by Corelli (in the style of Tartini); arr. (Box-folder 4/10)
    - [Variations on a theme by Corelli (in the style of Tartini); arr. (Sketch)], Holograph sketch for violin & organ, in ink; 2 p.; Uniform title: Variations on a theme by Corelli (in the style of Tartini); arr. (Sketch) (Box-folder 4/11)